<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on Brian Osborne</title><link>http://www.example.com/posts/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on Brian Osborne</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 28 Mar 2021 00:00:00 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://www.example.com/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Introducing the Editoria11y Drupal module</title><link>http://www.example.com/blog/introducing-the-editoria11y-drupal-module/</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 Mar 2021 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>http://www.example.com/blog/introducing-the-editoria11y-drupal-module/</guid><description>John Jameson, a digital accessibility developer and colleague of mine, has been working hard for months on a new accessibility module for Drupal module Editoria11y.
Editoria11y (editorial accessibility) is a user-friendly accessibility checker that addresses three critical needs for content authors:
It runs automatically. Modern spellcheck works so well because it is always running; put spellcheck behind a button and few users remember to run it! It runs in context.</description></item><item><title>Introducing the Decorative Image Widget Drupal module</title><link>http://www.example.com/blog/introducing-the-decorative-image-widget-drupal-module/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Jan 2021 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>http://www.example.com/blog/introducing-the-decorative-image-widget-drupal-module/</guid><description>Drupal&amp;rsquo;s Problem With Decorative Images Decorative images are those that should not be described to assistive technology like screen readers. A simple example is a fancy image of a decorative border that you insert at the end of a news article.
Supporting decorative images in Drupal is quite straight forward. Images fields can be set to collect alternative text but not require it. When left blank, Drupal will output an empty alt attribute for the image element, indicating to screen readers the image should be ignored.</description></item><item><title>How Drupal's Dynamic Page Cache Delivers Extremely Fast 404 Pages</title><link>http://www.example.com/blog/how-drupals-dynamic-page-cache-delivers-extremely-fast-404-pages/</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 Dec 2020 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>http://www.example.com/blog/how-drupals-dynamic-page-cache-delivers-extremely-fast-404-pages/</guid><description>Lately I&amp;rsquo;ve been working to improve the response time of 404 pages on some Drupal 8 sites I help maintain. Depending on the complexity of the site and the status of Drupal&amp;rsquo;s various cache layers, Drupal can be quite slow to generate a full page response, even for a 404 page. These sites I maintain are occasionally subjected to aggressive security penetration scans which generate a ton of 404 responses for completely unique URLs.</description></item><item><title>Introducing the Media Entity File Replace module</title><link>http://www.example.com/blog/introducing-the-media-entity-file-replace-module/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>http://www.example.com/blog/introducing-the-media-entity-file-replace-module/</guid><description>The Problem Replacing files uploaded to your Drupal site can be very frustrating. In most cases, when an editor wants to replace a document, they want to keep the exact same filename and filepath and just overwrite the contents of the file. This is important in cases where the file is linked to elsewhere throughout the website or on other websites outside of the editors control. If you use the media module to manage documents on your site, you&amp;rsquo;ll quickly discover that it&amp;rsquo;s not possible to upload a replacement file for a document and keep the same filename.</description></item><item><title>The challenge of using responsive image styles with Drupal's layout builder</title><link>http://www.example.com/blog/the-challenge-of-using-responsive-image-styles-with-drupals-layout-builder/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Apr 2019 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>http://www.example.com/blog/the-challenge-of-using-responsive-image-styles-with-drupals-layout-builder/</guid><description>Responsive images overview As screen resolutions and pixel densities continue to climb year after year, it&amp;rsquo;s becoming more important to deliver the best possible image quality to your visitors. The easy way out is to deliver a single high resolution image, but this can have a real impact on page load time &amp;amp; bandwidth usage, especially for visitors on mobile devices &amp;amp; networks. The better solution is to deliver the appropriately sized image based on the screen width/resolution of the browser.</description></item><item><title>Adding MySQL UTF8MB4 support to hundreds of Drupal 7 multi-sites</title><link>http://www.example.com/blog/adding-mysql-utf8mb4-support-to-hundreds-of-drupal-7-multi-sites/</link><pubDate>Sat, 21 Jul 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>http://www.example.com/blog/adding-mysql-utf8mb4-support-to-hundreds-of-drupal-7-multi-sites/</guid><description>Unicode characters encoded using UTF8 can technically use 1 to 4 bytes to represent a single character. However, older versions of MySQL only provided support for storing UTF8 encoded characters that used 1 to 3 bytes. This was enough to cover the most commonly used characters, but is not suitable for applications that accept user input where any character can be submitted (like emojis, which use 4 bytes). Newer versions of MySQL provide a character encoding called utf8mb4 to fix this issue.</description></item><item><title>Overriding module configuration in a Drupal 8 installation profile (with some "gotchas")</title><link>http://www.example.com/blog/overriding-module-configuration-in-a-drupal-8-installation-profile-with-some-gotchas/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Mar 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>http://www.example.com/blog/overriding-module-configuration-in-a-drupal-8-installation-profile-with-some-gotchas/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m working in creating a Drupal 8 installation profile and learning how they can override default configuration that its modules provide at install time.
All Drupal 8 modules can provide a set of configuration that should be installed to the site when the module is installed. This configuration is placed in the module&amp;rsquo;s config/install or config/optional directory. The only difference is that the configuration objects placed in the config/optional directory will only be installed if all of their dependencies are met.</description></item><item><title>Importing Images Within an RSS Feed Using the Drupal 7 Feeds Module</title><link>http://www.example.com/blog/importing-images-within-an-rss-feed-using-the-drupal-7-feeds-module/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>http://www.example.com/blog/importing-images-within-an-rss-feed-using-the-drupal-7-feeds-module/</guid><description>Yes, a blog post about Drupal 7!
I recently worked on an enhancement for a large multi-site Drupal 7 platform to allow its users to import news articles from RSS feeds. Pretty simple request, and given the maturity of the Drupal 7 contrib module ecosystem, it wasn&amp;rsquo;t too difficult to implement.
One somewhat interesting requirement was that images from the RSS feed be imported to an image field on the news article content type.</description></item><item><title>Keeping a view of upcoming events fresh in Drupal 8</title><link>http://www.example.com/blog/keeping-a-view-of-upcoming-events-fresh-in-drupal-8/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 May 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>http://www.example.com/blog/keeping-a-view-of-upcoming-events-fresh-in-drupal-8/</guid><description>Imagine you have a view that lists upcoming events on your Drupal 8 site. There&amp;rsquo;s a date filter that filters out any event who&amp;rsquo;s start date is less than the current date. This works great until you realize that the output of the view will be cached in one or many places (dynamic page cache, internal page cache, varnish, etc). Once it&amp;rsquo;s cached, views doesn&amp;rsquo;t execute the query and can&amp;rsquo;t compare the date to the current time, so you may get older events sticking around.</description></item><item><title>Preventing Drupal 8 from applying image styles to GIFs to preserve animation</title><link>http://www.example.com/blog/preventing-drupal-8-from-applying-image-styles-to-gifs-to-preserve-animation/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Dec 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>http://www.example.com/blog/preventing-drupal-8-from-applying-image-styles-to-gifs-to-preserve-animation/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m working on a site where the editorial staff may occasionally produce animated GIFs and place them in an article. Image styles and animated GIFs in Drupal don&amp;rsquo;t play nice out of the box. Drupal&amp;rsquo;s standard image processing library, GD, does not preserve GIF animation when it processes them, so any image styles applied to the image will remove the animation. The ImageMagick image processing library is capable of preserving animation, but I believe the only way is to first coalesce the GIF which dramatically increases the output size which in unacceptable for this project (my sample 200kb GIF ballooned to nearly 2mb).</description></item><item><title>Escaping input for custom Twig Functions</title><link>http://www.example.com/blog/escaping-input-for-custom-twig-functions/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2015 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>http://www.example.com/blog/escaping-input-for-custom-twig-functions/</guid><description>I have a custom Twig function that will output a question mark icon with tooltipfunctionality from bootstrap. My Symfony twig extension class looks like this:
public function getFunctions()
{
return array(
new \Twig_SimpleFunction(
'tooltip_icon',
array($this, 'tooltipIcon'),
array('is_safe' =&amp;gt; array('html'))
),
);
}
public function tooltipIcon($text, array $options = array())
{
$defaults = array(
'placement' =&amp;gt; 'top',
);
$options += $defaults;
return '&amp;lt;span class=&amp;quot;glyphicon glyphicon-question-sign&amp;quot; data-toggle=&amp;quot;tooltip&amp;quot; data-placement=&amp;quot;' . $placement . '&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;' .</description></item><item><title>Using the 'Dynamic Cache' Module to Programmatically Disable Page Caching</title><link>http://www.example.com/blog/using-the-dynamic-cache-module-to-programmatically-disable-page-caching/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Feb 2014 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>http://www.example.com/blog/using-the-dynamic-cache-module-to-programmatically-disable-page-caching/</guid><description>I recently worked on porting over a website to Drupal that had several dynamic elements throughout the site depending on the IP address of the user. Different content could be shown depending on if the user was within a local network, a larger local network, or completely outside the network.
When porting the site over, I realized that it wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be possible to enable page caching for any page that had this dynamic content on it.</description></item><item><title>Creating a Resource Calendar in Drupal 7</title><link>http://www.example.com/blog/creating-a-resource-calendar-in-drupal-7/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2014 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>http://www.example.com/blog/creating-a-resource-calendar-in-drupal-7/</guid><description>I just finished up a small project at work to create a basic resource management calendar to visualize and manage room and other asset reservations. The idea was to have a calendar that displayed reservations for various resources and allow privileged users the ability add reservations themselves. The existing system that was being used was a pain to work with and very time consuming - and I knew this could be done easily in Drupal 7.</description></item><item><title>Digging Deeper into Drupal Page Caching</title><link>http://www.example.com/blog/digging-deeper-into-drupal-page-caching/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2013 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>http://www.example.com/blog/digging-deeper-into-drupal-page-caching/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been away from full time Drupal development for a couple of years and have recently returned, this time making a commitment improve my understanding of core. There&amp;rsquo;s a lot of information out there on Drupal caching, but I found much of it to be fragmented and outdated (Drupal 6). I wanted to provide a more comprehensive look at Drupal 7&amp;rsquo;s core caching, explaining how some of this stuff is actually working under the hood.</description></item><item><title>The Importance of Character Encodings</title><link>http://www.example.com/blog/the-importance-of-character-encodings/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2013 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>http://www.example.com/blog/the-importance-of-character-encodings/</guid><description>I recently started on a project that involves migrating some data from a legacy app &amp;amp; database into Drupal. The old application is a collection of PHP scripts that basically just generate forms, accept data, insert said data into the database, and output it on a website. Pretty simple stuff - there&amp;rsquo;s not a whole lot going on. It was developed long before many of the popular CMS&amp;rsquo;s and frameworks came to be, and probably before people really started paying attention to the character encoding of their data.</description></item><item><title>Quick and dirty script logging</title><link>http://www.example.com/blog/quick-and-dirty-script-logging/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Sep 2013 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>http://www.example.com/blog/quick-and-dirty-script-logging/</guid><description>I write quite a bit of Ruby scripts that run at scheduled intervals via cron, and need a way to monitor their output easily. Ruby has a few popular logging solutions, including one that is part of the standard library, that can be fairly easy to integrate into your script.
For a quick script, I find it unnecessary to add the overhead of a logger class and get it all set up.</description></item><item><title>Waterwheel Carousel 2.2 released</title><link>http://www.example.com/blog/waterwheel-carousel-2.2-released/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2013 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>http://www.example.com/blog/waterwheel-carousel-2.2-released/</guid><description>This is a small release. A lot of people have been having trouble with the carousel not loading properly, and I&amp;rsquo;m sure this is because of the image preloader. The carousel has always worked by first attempting to forcefully load all of the images before initializing. This is a well known difficulty within the javascript community. I thought I had a pretty solid preloader finally figured out, but alas people continue to have issues with it.</description></item><item><title>Waterwheel Carousel 2.1 released</title><link>http://www.example.com/blog/waterwheel-carousel-2.1-released/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2013 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>http://www.example.com/blog/waterwheel-carousel-2.1-released/</guid><description>Managed to get out three updates to the Waterwheel Carousel this weekend. I&amp;rsquo;m working towards getting this carousel to replace the Feature Carousel - it doesn&amp;rsquo;t make sense for me to maintain both of them when they are already fairly similar.
Changes:
Bug fix to the image preloader - hopefully this fixes the issues with IE The images can now move to a hidden position behind the center, instead of fading to nothingness at the edge.</description></item><item><title>Migrating from Linode to Digital Ocean</title><link>http://www.example.com/blog/migrating-from-linode-to-digital-ocean/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Mar 2013 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>http://www.example.com/blog/migrating-from-linode-to-digital-ocean/</guid><description>A co-worker of mine recently came back from a Ruby meetup in NYC, where he heard of a new VPS hosting company called Digital Ocean. There&amp;rsquo;s certainly no shortage of VPS hosts around now, but Digital Ocean appeared very appealing because it&amp;rsquo;s lowest tiered plan cost just $5 a month &amp;ndash; too good to be true, right? The features you get with that low plan are nothing to scuff at either, giving you 512MB of memory, 20GB of SSD, and 1TB of bandwidth.</description></item><item><title>Waterwheel Carousel 2.0 Released</title><link>http://www.example.com/blog/waterwheel-carousel-2.0-released/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Feb 2013 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>http://www.example.com/blog/waterwheel-carousel-2.0-released/</guid><description>After a lengthy development hiatus, I&amp;rsquo;ve added a significant release to the waterwheel carousel. What was originally slated for a 1.4 release has been bumped to a 2.0 release. The release includes lots of bug fixes and features, most important of which is full &amp;ldquo;circular&amp;rdquo; support. Take a look at the changelog on github to see a list of the changes.
Now that the waterwheel carousel has full circular support, there&amp;rsquo;s only a few missing features that it lacks from the feature carousel.</description></item><item><title>Installing ruby-debug in Ruby 1.9.3</title><link>http://www.example.com/blog/installing-ruby-debug-in-ruby-1.9.3/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Mar 2012 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>http://www.example.com/blog/installing-ruby-debug-in-ruby-1.9.3/</guid><description>Update: You can now use the debugger gem to circumvent this issue. Or better yet, use pry
I&amp;rsquo;ve been working in a development environment that required an earlier verison of Ruby (1.8.7) that worked well with the ruby-debug gem. This gem is widly used and has some nice &amp;ldquo;get to know it&amp;rdquo; text in the rails guides.
However, as I moved to a better environment to develop some playground applications with the latest and greatest Ruby and Rails, I ran into a snag when attempting to use ruby-debug.</description></item><item><title>Determine PHP memory usage for anonymous users</title><link>http://www.example.com/blog/determine-php-memory-usage-for-anonymous-users/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Feb 2012 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>http://www.example.com/blog/determine-php-memory-usage-for-anonymous-users/</guid><description>In case you&amp;rsquo;ve been living under a rock for the past two years: Drupal 7 is known to use quite a bit of PHP memory everytime a page is loaded. I won&amp;rsquo;t get into anything why that is and why it&amp;rsquo;s such a big jump from Drupal 6 (I&amp;rsquo;m in no position to comment on that), but what you need to know is that Drupal 7 can easily use 40-50 MB per page load for a small to mid size website, and much much more for larger websites.</description></item><item><title>Looking at the new FullCalendar module for Drupal</title><link>http://www.example.com/blog/looking-at-the-new-fullcalendar-module-for-drupal/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Feb 2012 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>http://www.example.com/blog/looking-at-the-new-fullcalendar-module-for-drupal/</guid><description>Last weekend @ DrupalCamp New Jersey, Tim Plunkett presented a wonderful alternative of the Calendar module for Drupal, called FullCalendar. I could be wrong, but I believe this was the first presentation given on the module which is very close to a stable release for Drupal 7.
Many who have wanted to create calendars in Drupal have used the time-tested Calendar module that&amp;rsquo;s been around for years. I haven&amp;rsquo;t used that module in about a year, and I don&amp;rsquo;t know what sort of advancements have been made in the Drupal 7 version of the module (also close to a stable release it seems).</description></item><item><title>Client-side content inclusion in Drupal</title><link>http://www.example.com/blog/client-side-content-inclusion-in-drupal/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Feb 2012 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>http://www.example.com/blog/client-side-content-inclusion-in-drupal/</guid><description>At DrupalCamp NJ (the first ever, glad NJ is getting some love!), Jesse Beach from Acquia presented her thoughts how content is served in Drupal, and how to fix some problems that have surfaced over the years of web development. The traditional method for serving content to browsers is to have the server send off the entire DOM all at once. This was okay when websites were much simpler and developers created them using individual HTML pages, but websites are much more complicated now and often behind a complex CMS like Drupal.</description></item><item><title>What Adobe is Doing to Stay Relevant on the Web</title><link>http://www.example.com/blog/what-adobe-is-doing-to-stay-relevant-on-the-web/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Jan 2012 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>http://www.example.com/blog/what-adobe-is-doing-to-stay-relevant-on-the-web/</guid><description>I recently attended a PANMA event in Philly focusing on HTML5 &amp;amp; Adobe. Terry Ryan from Adobe gave a stellar presentation on a few things the company is doing to stay relevant in the rapidly changing web. It&amp;rsquo;s no secret that Flash as we know it is dying off. A few months ago, Apple officially said they will not support it on iOS devices, and whatever you may think about that, the general consensus is that Flash will not be a player for much longer.</description></item><item><title>Modifying FAPI output with Drupal 7's renderable arrays</title><link>http://www.example.com/blog/modifying-fapi-output-with-drupal-7s-renderable-arrays/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Jan 2012 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>http://www.example.com/blog/modifying-fapi-output-with-drupal-7s-renderable-arrays/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on a project that requires the search block look a very specific way. The text input and submit button needed to be directly next to one another. I could probably get it done with just CSS, but all the extra markup in the search block was really bothering me.
I&amp;rsquo;ve heard great things about Drupal 7&amp;rsquo;s new rendering system, but it was pretty mysterious to me. I remember attending a session about it @ DrupalCon Chicago but it was a bit over my head at the time.</description></item><item><title>Creating a primary and secondary horizontal menu in Drupal</title><link>http://www.example.com/blog/creating-a-primary-and-secondary-horizontal-menu-in-drupal/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Jan 2012 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>http://www.example.com/blog/creating-a-primary-and-secondary-horizontal-menu-in-drupal/</guid><description>This is a fairly common menu structure for Drupal developers to deal with, and depending on how it functions, it could be super easy. Here&amp;rsquo;s the scenario: you need to display the 1st level of links in a menu horizontally, and the 2nd level in that same menu right beneath it.
There are at least two different ways that this can be implemented. The first is a static approach, where you do NOT need to show children of each primary link when hovering.</description></item><item><title>Why You Should Use A 3rd Party Comment Service</title><link>http://www.example.com/blog/why-you-should-use-a-3rd-party-comment-service/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Dec 2011 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>http://www.example.com/blog/why-you-should-use-a-3rd-party-comment-service/</guid><description>Drupal is a wonderful content management system. Any Drupal web developer will tell you that there seems to be a module for anything you can think of. For the most part, this is what makes Drupal so great. The community support is second to none and it&amp;rsquo;s never too hard to find a module that suites your needs.
With that said, it&amp;rsquo;s important to understand when there may be something other than Drupal that you should be using for a particular functionality.</description></item><item><title>HTML5 - What a Project Manager Should Know</title><link>http://www.example.com/blog/html5-what-a-project-manager-should-know/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2011 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>http://www.example.com/blog/html5-what-a-project-manager-should-know/</guid><description>HTML5 has become quite the buzz word lately, and it&amp;rsquo;s important for people in both developer roles and project management roles to understand what it really is. The term has been around long enough that clients are aware of it, and may begin to ask &amp;ldquo;so how will you incorporate HTML5 into our website?&amp;rdquo; Not knowing how to answer this could be disastrous when attempting to gain the trust of a potential client.</description></item><item><title>Feature Carousel v1.3 Released</title><link>http://www.example.com/blog/feature-carousel-v1.3-released/</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Nov 2011 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>http://www.example.com/blog/feature-carousel-v1.3-released/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve just tagged version 1.3 of the Feature Carousel. This release includes the following updates
Changed structure to support public functions Added four public functions to control carousel Fixed image preloader to work in IE versions A few minor bug fixes The preloader should finally be fixed - so I hope to see much less people commenting about it :). I&amp;rsquo;ve also packaged it up with new pictures that are actual photographs.</description></item><item><title>Waterwheel version 1.3 released!</title><link>http://www.example.com/blog/waterwheel-version-1.3-released/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 May 2011 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>http://www.example.com/blog/waterwheel-version-1.3-released/</guid><description>Finally got the time to put out the next release. I&amp;rsquo;m pretty happy with this one - I tied up a lot of loose ends and common feature requests. The most important feature is the circular support I added in. A lot of people desired to have a true infinite ciruclar effect (so there are no edges or walls), and I was planning on that for v1.4. However I was messing around with some ideas and in the meantime added in support for resetting the carousel to the opposite side very quickly when an edge is hit.</description></item><item><title>DrupalCon Chicago 2011 Recap - Part 3</title><link>http://www.example.com/blog/drupalcon-chicago-2011-recap-part-3/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Apr 2011 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>http://www.example.com/blog/drupalcon-chicago-2011-recap-part-3/</guid><description>I had a great time at DrupalCon. This was the last day of presentations before I had to catch my flight back to Philly. Because of my flight time I had to miss the last session track and any meet ups that night, but such is life. My favorite presentation of the conference was on this day: Drupal Commerce. I look forward to exploring all of these modules, ideas, and technologies in the upcoming months!</description></item><item><title>DrupalCon Chicago 2011 Recap - Part 2</title><link>http://www.example.com/blog/drupalcon-chicago-2011-recap-part-2/</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Mar 2011 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>http://www.example.com/blog/drupalcon-chicago-2011-recap-part-2/</guid><description>This is the second entry in recapping my trip to Chicago for DrupalCon. On the opening night (Monday), a party was held at the Field Museum of Natural History. Beer, wine, and plenty of food was served as we were all free to roam around most of the building. The most impressive was certainly Sue, the world&amp;rsquo;s most complete T-Rex fossil. Certainly worth checking out if you are end up in Chicago.</description></item><item><title>DrupalCon Chicago 2011 Recap - Part 1</title><link>http://www.example.com/blog/drupalcon-chicago-2011-recap-part-1/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Mar 2011 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>http://www.example.com/blog/drupalcon-chicago-2011-recap-part-1/</guid><description>Hello all&amp;hellip; I&amp;rsquo;ve just returned from my first DrupalCon this past week, and it was a great time &amp;amp; experience. It was also the first time I was on a commercial flight, but all went well. I&amp;rsquo;ve been developing sites in Drupal for about a year now and couldn&amp;rsquo;t have been more excited to head to Chicago to check out the bi-annual conference. Chicago is certainly a beautiful city!
There were certainly over 3,000 people at the Sheraton Towers in downtown Chicago, and it was a bit mind-boggling to see the insane amount of people equally obsessed with Drupal as I am.</description></item><item><title>Version 1.1 Feature Carousel, Version 1.2.1 of Waterwheel Carousel</title><link>http://www.example.com/blog/version-1.1-feature-carousel-version-1.2.1-of-waterwheel-carousel/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Feb 2011 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>http://www.example.com/blog/version-1.1-feature-carousel-version-1.2.1-of-waterwheel-carousel/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve managed to get out a new release of the Feature Carousel. It includes some common feature requests such as next and previous control arrows. In fact, version 1.0 supported them in the code but I never actually utilized them in the HTML for demonstrating.
I&amp;rsquo;ve altered the options and faq pages as well. Six new options were added for the feature carousel, including three callback functions that a few people have asked about.</description></item><item><title>Development roadmaps...</title><link>http://www.example.com/blog/development-roadmaps.../</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Jan 2011 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>http://www.example.com/blog/development-roadmaps.../</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve added a development roadmap for both carousels; it outlines what I have in mind for future releases. If you&amp;rsquo;d like to see a feature added to either of the carousels, go ahead an comment on the roadmap page to have it added. If it&amp;rsquo;s not too crazy, I can probably work it in. A large request for the feature carousel is to be able to display more than one flanking &amp;ldquo;feature&amp;rdquo; story.</description></item><item><title>Waterwheel version 1.2 release</title><link>http://www.example.com/blog/waterwheel-version-1.2-release/</link><pubDate>Sat, 15 Jan 2011 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>http://www.example.com/blog/waterwheel-version-1.2-release/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve just commited the v1.2 tag for the waterwheel carousel. You can download this version on GitHub; just select the Download button, and then the link for v1.2. This version includes a few improvements that have been bothering users and I alike for a while. Here is a short summary (I may have missed something&amp;hellip;):
support for more than one carousel on a page autoplay works properly control box with previous next added a bunch of example cases to index.</description></item><item><title>New website</title><link>http://www.example.com/blog/new-website/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Jan 2011 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>http://www.example.com/blog/new-website/</guid><description>Hello all..
This has been a long time coming, but I finally relaunched this website. The old site has been taken down and will never be seen again&amp;hellip; I originally threw it up in a few days just to showcase my two jQuery plug-ins. I had just about no experience using Drupal (or any other web framework for that matter) at the time that site went up and it was pretty poorly made.</description></item></channel></rss>